Curriculum Vitae

Amsan. E, B.com, MLIS,

1/31 Poonjolai Nagar, Panayappatti,

Pudukkottai, - 622402

Email: <u>amsan2020@gmail.com</u> Phone: +91- 9700616637



Career Objective:

Fulfilled the needs of the readers regarding any book or knowledge from database, also assisted them in locating the database.

Career Summary:

Work experience of 6 years and I was worked as a IRC Associate at Accenture India – Hyderabad. Previously I was worked as a Librarian at Alpha College of Engineering-Chennai. Well-acquainted with the computer operations to keep a track of the book inventory in the library, have been responsible for updating the inventory of the library by studying the reviews of various books, their demands, etc.

Professional Experience:

Designation: IRC Associate (Information Resource Centre), Accenture India, Hyderabad. (Sep 1,2016 – Aug 31, 2020) Roles and Responsibilities:

- Respond to daily on-site requests for information.
- Train library users to effectively search the Library catalogue, Internet and other electronic resources.
- Provide an interlibrary loan service for both book and audiovisual materials and maintain Records.
- Maintain records for the interlibrary loan service.
- Contacting book fair events and Managing Learning and Knowledge management trainings
- Maintain circulation files, records and statistics.

Previous Work Experience:

Designation: Librarian, Alpha College of Engineering, Chennai. (March 2016 – Aug 2016).

Roles and Responsibilities:

- Maintain a record of all the members of the library.
- Issue membership cards to new members, renew memberships, etc.
- Update the library with the latest books.
- Supervise the maintenance and discipline of the library.
- Using Dspace maintaining old Q bank and College events photos.

Designation: Library Intern, LRC, ISB, Hyderabad, (<u>February 2014–October 2015</u>) **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Work in coordination with the Chief Librarian.
- Make proper entries regarding the new books using the data management software.
- Supervise the maintenance and discipline of the library.
- Compile the monthly reports and get them approved from the Librarian.
- Membership maintaining in VTLS tool.

Designation: Library Trainee, SRM Medical College & Research Center, SRM University, (May 2013- Feb, 2014) **Roles and Responsibilities:**

- Maintaining the library as well as Computer systems.
- Making entries of the new books introduced in the library.
- Understanding the requirements of students and placing orders for new books accordingly.

Qualifications:

Post-Graduation:

Master of Library and Information Science-

2013 (82%) Alagappa University, Karaikudi.

Graduation:

• **Bachelor of Commerce** – 2011 (60 %) Ganesar college of art & science, Melaisivapuri, Bharathidasan University, Trichy.

Extra-Oualifications:

 \triangleright Diploma in Computer Application (D.C.A) – 2008,

Diploma in Yoga -2011

National & International Papers:

- ❖ National Conference On Digital Resource Initiatives in Libraries (DRIL)**Top Social Networking & Social Media Websites: A Communication Tool**" V.S.B.Engineering College, Karur − 639 111.Tamilnadu.
- ❖ International Journal of Digital Library Services on "Effective Use of E-Resource Materials among Students of JJ College of Engineering and Technology: A Study" Vol, 3. Issue-2 April June 2013,
- ❖ National Seminar on Application and Relevance of E-Resources"- AREAL-2013 Alagappa University, Karaikudi.
- "Effecty use of RSS Feed in Digital Library"

IT-Skills:

Working knowledge of Local area network, E-mail facility, online access to Library databases on Internet As online journals, online catalogue, and E-Resources, etc. Database Management, Information Retrieval Management and Data conversion.

Knowledge of Digital Library Software

D-space Greenstone E-prints

Knowledge of Library Software

KOHA VTLS SOUL 2.0

Area of Interest

Digital Libraries using D-Space & Greenstone, Digital Libraries Software- Classification of books through DDC and UDC-Consortium formation and subscription of e-journals/Database-Content Management- Creation Web Pages and Design and Development of Databases Information - Digital Collection, IT applications in libraries, Library automation and networking and Information Management

Extra-Curricular Activities:

• Participated in cultural program College- 2011

• Winner of Inter-College Competition in Multi-talented person at Alagappa University -2013

Achievements:

- Awarded with the 'Best Student Award' for the year 2009
- Won first prize in Paper Presentation Competition organized for literature students
- Received an appreciation letter from the Librarian for dedication and smart work.
- Ranked the 'Most Popular Employee' as per the customer satisfaction survey conducted with the members of the library

References:

Dr. S P. Balasubramanian, Associate Director, LRC, ISB, Hyderabad, India.

Mr. V. Raja, Scientist-B, INFLIBNET, Gujarat, India.

Dr. V. Chitra, Librarian, SRM Medical College, SRM University, Chennai.

Dr. Thanuskodi, HOD, DLIS, Alagappa University, Karaikudi-630 003

Dr. Jay Shankar, Asset Professor, DLIS, Alagappa University, Karaikudi-630 003.

Signature:

(Amsan. E)